<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <link>http://uaarg.com</link>
    <atom:link href="http://uaarg.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description></description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2015 20:15:20 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2015 20:15:20 +0000</lastBuildDate>

    
    
    <item>
      <title>January Update</title>
      <link>http://uaarg.com/2015/01/25/january-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://uaarg.com/2015/01/25/january-update</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hey world out there. We have been a bit slacking in updating our blog, hopefully that will change for this semester.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;highlights_from_last_semester&quot;&gt;Highlights from last semester:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New Plane - If you recall shortly before US competition our plane had a fateful water landing. During the summer plans were set for our new plane. We have decided to continue using the EPP foam airframe that last year’s capstone group had developed. In the first two weeks of school Andrew, Cindy and Rijesh were busy busy putting the plane together. Andrew made all the modifications and assemebled the airframe, Cindy did her usual imaging magic, and Rijesh brought the electronics and autopilot all together. Our first flight was a success! (see below)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fully Autonomous Flight - On our aircrafts maiden flight, we managed to get the plane to a fully autonomous state. The plane successfully navigated through three different waypoints on either side of the flying field, changing altitude by to 200m.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kick-off Meeting - We held our annual kick off meeting. We had many people attend and the club room was quite packed last semester. We are hoping that will be the same for this semester as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the_coming_semester&quot;&gt;The Coming Semester&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have many projects planned for this semester. I’ll try to detail more of what we are doing in the coming weeks as well as the status of our system.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A new site for UAARG</title>
      <link>http://uaarg.com/2014/07/22/new-site/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://uaarg.com/2014/07/22/new-site</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the new site for the U of A Aerial Robotics Group, now hosted on Github Pages!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the content from our old blog will be migrated over soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;some_examples_of_formatting&quot;&gt;Some examples of formatting&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
import math

sine_list = []
for i in range(19):
    sine_list.append(math.sin(i)     
print(sine_list)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Two crashes and rethinking the plane</title>
      <link>http://uaarg.com/2014/06/21/two-crashes-and-rethinking-plane/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://uaarg.com/2014/06/21/two-crashes-and-rethinking-plane</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello from the AUVSI Student UAS competition! The 4 of us – Joe, Paul, Cindy, and Rijesh – are currently in Lexington Park, Maryland.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you may have heard, we had some show-stopping events just before the AUVSI competition. Inconceivable, our last remaining airframe, crashed twice into the North Saskatchewan River in the days just before the AUVSI Competition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-UVjnzF4vrpg/U6X44ycADJI/AAAAAAAAATg/qDnh90UarMU/s1600/WP_20140615_14_23_52_Pro.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Crash #1, with the boaters that rescued Inconceivable for us&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-AlVd6IcR444/U6X44iVIIhI/AAAAAAAAATc/bFAuvgu1wdc/s1600/WP_20140616_20_29_50_Pro.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Crash #2, when we weren’t so lucky&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The causes of the crashes are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Crash 1: Inconceivable has flaperons that were engaged on takeoff. These were not turned off after takeoff, meaning that the aileron servos could not move enough to have the plane bank as intended. The plane went into a severe right bank, lost altitude quickly, and crashed into the river. Thanks to the boaters in the picture above, we were able to recover the plane.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Crash 2: When tuning a pitch control loop in AUTO2, Inconceivable went into a severe pitch down and gained a significant amount of speed. The pilot was not able to recover Inconceivable in time. Because Inconceivable was pointing north at the time this happened, it descended into the river. These crashes were due to a combination of poor planning, a limited amount of time to tune and develop our autopilot, and pilot error. As a consequence, we have no functioning system right now, and are here at the competition as observers only.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve been starting to think about our next system. Because of the crashes, we are in need of a new airframe and a new camera system altogether. The EPP FPV airframe we previously had is out of stock, and we have been thinking about replacing our camera system for a while. Some ideas that have been floated for each of these include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A small foam delta wing airframe. We’ve had good experiences with Murphy and Inconceivable, our two EPP FPV foam aircraft. Foam offers less weight and cheaper and easier repairs in case of a crash. We’ve seen 3 separate teams here with very similar delta wing models, and have been talking to them about their experiences.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Another scientific imaging camera (with a wider-angle lens that what we had).&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;A DSLR or other Canon/Nikon consumer camera running with a tethered shooting software, so that we can read live images from the camera.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;A smartphone camera, with image processing happening on the phone.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are going to the awards banquet tonight; there will be a post later today about some of the events of the competition, as well as the competition results.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Canadian Competition Round Up and Proof of Flight</title>
      <link>http://uaarg.com/2014/06/05/canadian-competition-round-up-and-proof/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://uaarg.com/2014/06/05/canadian-competition-round-up-and-proof</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So here are a few pictures from Canadian competition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-YMOr4gqR51Y/U352Msn8eFI/AAAAAAAA
AQ8/b9aKwUkxvr8/s1600/5851.JPG&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-YMOr4gqR51Y/U352Msn8eFI/AAAAAAAAAQ8/b9aKwUkxvr
8/s1600/5851.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-07iU4cTlQuM/U352Nn7NdFI/AAAAAAAA
ARI/ApZoyXa12qc/s1600/5854.JPG&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-07iU4cTlQuM/U352Nn7NdFI/AAAAAAAAARI/ApZoyXa12q
c/s1600/5854.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-KQ2_ui9eyGA/U352acAWu9I/AAAAAAAA
ARs/1ecDPaqsO70/s1600/5861.JPG&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-KQ2_ui9eyGA/U352acAWu9I/AAAAAAAAARs/1ecDPaqsO7
0/s1600/5861.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-QyUfCVQiDO0/U352T27EPOI/AAAAAAAA
ARc/Qk10oSY9pk4/s1600/5870.JPG&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-QyUfCVQiDO0/U352T27EPOI/AAAAAAAAARc/Qk10oSY9pk
4/s1600/5870.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-
mQQ3wWSmudE/U352SaluGlI/AAAAAAAAARU/AtvuocbTq8U/s1600/5867.JPG&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-mQQ3wWSmudE/U3
52SaluGlI/AAAAAAAAARU/AtvuocbTq8U/s1600/5867.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-iGzk5LkcV3A/U352XLMgySI/AAAAAAAA
ARk/Owrr_ULGAf4/s1600/5877.JPG&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-iGzk5LkcV3A/U352XLMgySI/AAAAAAAAARk/Owrr_ULGAf
4/s1600/5877.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-BGIYbjx3EnE/U5D27o3UI7I/AAAAAAAA
ASc/Zp2_T2O2Gtc/s1600/5475.JPG&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-BGIYbjx3EnE/U5D27o3UI7I/AAAAAAAAASc/Zp2_T2O2Gt
c/s1600/5475.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-
lA2GKQ0cGVc/U5D26NnbT1I/AAAAAAAAASY/BJFssA8ot-Y/s1600/5472.JPG&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-lA2GKQ0cGVc/U5
D26NnbT1I/AAAAAAAAASY/BJFssA8ot-Y/s1600/5472.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-ESPDAgcEdDs/U352eEc1iXI/AAAAAAAAAR0/o_QCE-
_Lu8U/s1600/6238.JPG&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-ESPDAgcEdDs/U352eEc1iXI/AAAAAAAAAR0/o_QCE-
_Lu8U/s1600/6238.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-ZA-
BuNm2GM0/U352ejnwAaI/AAAAAAAAAR4/MGmpg-NjoQA/s1600/6241.JPG&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-ZA-BuNm2GM0/U352ejnwAaI/AAAAAAAAAR4/MGmpg-
NjoQA/s1600/6241.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Team UAARG is way more mature than Murphy&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally here is a proof of flight video of our system we are taking to US competition.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Canadian Competition, Day 4</title>
      <link>http://uaarg.com/2014/05/05/canadian-competition-day-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://uaarg.com/2014/05/05/canadian-competition-day-4</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This morning, Team Murphy flew. They were able to capture images and everything seemed well. Unfortunately midway through the flight their plane experienced a loss of R/C signal, and nose-dived into the ground from upwards of 50 meters. This was their last time to fly and the crash occurred during the early portion of the flight. As a result, they were not able to geo reference or visually spot any of the targets. Team Murphy was in high spirits despite this, and are raring to rebuild their system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-Y39Hr7bBqsY/U2dr72K-
rxI/AAAAAAAAAQQ/8uuwJAOztY4/s1600/WP_20140504_08_06_11_Pro.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-Y39Hr7bBqsY/U2dr72K-
rxI/AAAAAAAAAQQ/8uuwJAOztY4/s1600/WP_20140504_08_06_11_Pro.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Team Murphy looking chipper&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The imaging portion of team UAARG had a late night last night. On the drive to Manitoba, we lost our single SD card containing our operating system running our imaging software. We had another, older backup; the imaging team stayed up to troubleshoot and try to get to a functional system. On the flight line, though, we had issues connecting to the onboard camera. Of the 40 minute time limit for our flying, we spent the first twenty trying to get good data from the camera again. Finally at the twenty minute mark we decided to just go with a quick RC flight. The RC flight performed far better than expected. The airframe and electronics were fairly untested and untrimmed but the plane handled with ease.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we brought the plane back to the ground, the imaging systems still weren’t working. Our camera wasn’t having data being read from it at all. Rijesh came up with the idea to donate his phone as a camera for the flight; a minute and lots of tape later, we were ready to go up. We did a quick 2 minute flight of the search area with the phone precariously taped in, just in the nick of time for the mission to end. We were super excited to review the video once we got back to the pits; lo and behold, we caught three targets!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-k9uMkWZD9vM/U2dsCNKd
09I/AAAAAAAAAQY/uI9VU0Hs7Rc/s1600/Screenshot+\(8\&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-k9uMkWZD9vM/U2dsCNKd09I/AAAAAAAAAQY/uI9VU0Hs7R
c/s1600/Screenshot+\(8\&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;.png)&lt;/a&gt;.png)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Locations of the 3 targets&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-a7zgoYJDQy4/U2dta26l
pkI/AAAAAAAAAQs/kdZmZLW_siA/s1600/Screenshot+\(7\&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-a7zgoYJDQy4/U2dta26lpkI/AAAAAAAAAQs/kdZmZLW_si
A/s1600/Screenshot+\(7\&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;.png)&lt;/a&gt;.png)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Picture of the tent&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After our flight, Arshad reconnected our camera and we were successfully able to run our imaging software and retrieve pictures encoded with geo-referencing data. Essentially, we managed to get all our systems fully functional and operational just as our mission timed out; our jerry-rigged system was that was put together just 2 days prior was functional and back to its original state! We pieced together our report with the data that we had captured, submitted it, and were done with the competition! We were all pretty thrilled and excited with our successes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The awards banquet was a pile of fun, as always, with a nod by the organizers to the U of A teams’ open, fun, and relaxed attitudes. (The precise term used to describe Team Murphy was “ballsy.”) Neither UAARG nor Team Murphy placed, but we were able to get some prize money. It’s not easy to get 100 people who are all interested in UAVs gathered in one room together, so we made the most of our time chatting with the organizers &amp;amp; judges &amp;amp; other teams and traded some contact information. The quality bar definitely seems to getting higher and higher each year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s been an exhilarating past couple of days. Let’s close this post here with an amazing shot of the Northern Lights that we were able to witness last night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-vqvFyArNjVs/U2dsE7TS1AI/AAAA
AAAAAQg/YWgywSP5-tA/s1600/P5030013.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-vqvFyArNjVs/U2dsE7TS1AI/AAAAAAAAAQg/YWgywSP5-t
A/s1600/P5030013.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is that Arshad or Usain Bolt? We can’t tell either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ll talk to you soon!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Canadian Competition, Day 3</title>
      <link>http://uaarg.com/2014/05/03/canadian-competition-day-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://uaarg.com/2014/05/03/canadian-competition-day-3</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With a pretty good night of sleep behind us, we trekked out to the pits. We were pretty burnt out the night before, but we had discovered a couple of problems: our wireless router was not turning on inside our hastily-reconstructed avionics box, and we had lost the SD card for the Pandaboard, taking all of our files with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We took a look at the wireless router in the morning, and soon found out that some of the voltage regulators we installed on the outside of the avionics box were burning hot. We soon found that our router was shorting up against our metal box, explaining our issues. We also had a fun scavenger hunt for the Pandaboard SD card, but this turned up nothing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our first flight time came up a bit sooner than we expected. We had some trouble installing our avionics box inside the plane and so carved away a good 10 minutes of our 45-minute flight time. Once we were there, the first priority was to get an R/C flight in, since the system hadn’t left the ground since the crash.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, we missed the same requirement this time that we did yesterday during our first Flight Readiness go-around: the throttle would not turn off if we lost the R/C link. As our flight time rolled on, we began to have more inexplicable issues: we had a weak R/C link, our telemetry link died, etc. Our time passed, and the plane hadn’t left the ground.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were lucky enough to have Julien from VAMUdeS, who were running a TWOG and PPM encoder system set up for their autopilot (just like us) help us out with the last failsafe condition; once we had that and tested it, our plane was ready to go. We were ready, but the weather wasn’t: it started snowing outside, delaying our second flight to tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was plenty of stuff to work on once we got back: going out and buying parts, restoring a backup of the Pandaboard’s card, replacing our voltage regulators, debugging the imaging software, etc. Mostly, though, it was a lot of sitting around and waiting. Here’s some pics of that:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-fGM-MZpQWhE/
U2WYzpYLNsI/AAAAAAAAAPs/tI2S95hyYRQ/s1600/WP_20140503_18_05_56_Pro.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-fGM-MZpQWhE/U2WYzpYLNsI/AAAAAAAAAPs/tI2S95hyYR
Q/s1600/WP_20140503_18_05_56_Pro.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cindy Xiao&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-Um44swkN14A/
U2WYyX_yalI/AAAAAAAAAPk/WUK_q9-94ik/s1600/WP_20140503_18_06_15_Pro.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-Um44swkN14A/U2WYyX_yalI/AAAAAAAAAPk/WUK_q9-94i
k/s1600/WP_20140503_18_06_15_Pro.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Arshad Husain&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-XQFr_-
m6Quc/U2WYxeLHInI/AAAAAAAAAPg/F0LBbmroHvk/s1600/WP_20140503_18_06_23_Pro.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-XQFr_-
m6Quc/U2WYxeLHInI/AAAAAAAAAPg/F0LBbmroHvk/s1600/WP_20140503_18_06_23_Pro.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Andrew Jowsey&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-FHOoRLatH74/
U2WY06QYVWI/AAAAAAAAAP4/k3s9te2oJ8Y/s1600/WP_20140503_18_06_39_Pro.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-FHOoRLatH74/U2WY06QYVWI/AAAAAAAAAP4/k3s9te2oJ8
Y/s1600/WP_20140503_18_06_39_Pro.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mark Pollock&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-lCkBw_o2SYE/
U2WY1x4llnI/AAAAAAAAAP8/BzPcSqP93-I/s1600/WP_20140503_18_07_03_Pro.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-lCkBw_o2SYE/U2WY1x4llnI/AAAAAAAAAP8/BzPcSqP93-
I/s1600/WP_20140503_18_07_03_Pro.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rijesh Augustine&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the Team Murphy side, they were out bright and early this morning - even more so than expected because of a crash from UVictoria beforehand. Because of a configuration mix-up, they weren’t able to get any pictures from their flight today. However, that was a quick fix, and the rest of their system was working perfectly well - lots of time to kill. Several hours of tomfoolery later, they made this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-
cloYjgX9kJI/U2WYISuJnoI/AAAAAAAAAPY/Y-f55N8MAcA/s1600/Screen+Shot+2014-05-03+a
t+7.08.52+PM.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-cloYjgX9kJI/U2WYISuJnoI/AAAAAAAAAPY/Y-f55N8MAc
A/s1600/Screen+Shot+2014-05-03+at+7.08.52+PM.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Flight path of Team Murphy’s plane and locations of images they took&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is data of the test flight they did yesterday. The yellow pins are the locations of the images taken during the flight, and the red path is the flight of the plane.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, both teams are in really good spirits. Team Murphy has their system entirely functional, Team UAARG is finally ready to fly. In addition to this, we got to travel around a lot to the other teams’ pits to learn more about their systems and share our woes. Interestingly, there seems to be very heavy sponsorship of a lot of teams this year, with loads of donated commercial hardware and imaging software making its way into teams’ systems. No matter what the system, though, everyone had issues with the wind or their RF links or their failsafes - it ended up being only 4 of 11 teams that actually flew today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tonight’s our free evening for hanging out. We’re going to hang out, rest up, and get ready for the last day!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-9X3naFt9E74/U2WXv
iUxy1I/AAAAAAAAAPM/WjcvC_jMw9Q/s1600/2014-05-03+19.18.07.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-9X3naFt9E74/U2WXviUxy1I/AAAAAAAAAPM/WjcvC_jMw9
Q/s1600/2014-05-03+19.18.07.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Team Murphy. Paul doesn’t know how to feel about this.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Canadian Competition Day 2</title>
      <link>http://uaarg.com/2014/05/02/candian-competition-day-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://uaarg.com/2014/05/02/candian-competition-day-2</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Day 2 of our competition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-iE2mzHSlMyQ/
U2REy5M4eeI/AAAAAAAAAO0/X5iTxdGpL2s/s1600/WP_20140502_17_15_29_Pro.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-iE2mzHSlMyQ/U2REy5M4eeI/AAAAAAAAAO0/X5iTxdGpL2
s/s1600/WP_20140502_17_15_29_Pro.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We arrived safely last night/this morning at 1:00am. The ride was filled with coding, learning and all-around competition preparation. As per our previous blog post, you may be aware that we had a few issues with our airframe, specifically the part when we decided to take it for a dip. Some quick executive decisions were made to purchase replacement parts and our entire lab was brought along with us to Manitoba. So at 1:00am there we were setting up our lab in one of the rooms. Exhibit A.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-6nOR6KMOSAE/U2RDirwJv8I/AAAAAAAAAOk/Nr-
DB32a9Ww/s1600/WP_20140502_03_02_39_Pro.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-6nOR6KMOSAE/U2RDirwJv8I/AAAAAAAAAOk/Nr-
DB32a9Ww/s1600/WP_20140502_03_02_39_Pro.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Busy away. Slowly one by one we fell and gave in to sleep. The majority of Team UAARG getting less than an hour of sleep. Going to bed a 6:00 and waking up at 7:00. Later this morning, the one time you can say that, we got up and presented our project proposal. At this competition, we are “contracted” to perform aerial surveillance, georeference targets, and calculate areas. We each spoke a bit about our respective fields with Cindy giving a general idea of why they should choose us as opposed to our competition. Following that we finished our final rewiring. At this point we were in a state where we could successfully capture images and tag them with telemetry data. The competition has a Flight Readiness Review(FRR). Basically a test we have to pass that ensures we have proper safety features present. At this point we should theoretically have passed the FRR but would have done so in a very round about way. Instead we decided to perform additional modifications to take the system to the very same level as the pre-crash plane. And that is just what we did. The first time the judges came to see our test we asked them to give us an extension, which they graciously gave. The second time the judges came by we thought we had everything configured correctly, but missed a requirement. Finally a third time we went out and passed the test with flying colours. Just on the nick of time as well. We performed a quick range test and noticed we were not receiving the same poor reception. It seems like our crash was caused by the metal cowl we had installed on the previous plane.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all though of the 11 teams only 2 teams actually flew today. UAARG did not manage to take our plane up for a test flight, but we were capable to do so. Alas we readied our plane 15 minutes too late.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From two days ago we had a drenched box full of electronics and now we have rebuilt the plane.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-NcD-JsZlPNQ/
U2RH0c7iluI/AAAAAAAAAPA/58TM5tdsAo4/s1600/WP_20140502_17_14_51_Pro.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-NcD-JsZlPNQ/U2RH0c7iluI/AAAAAAAAAPA/58TM5tdsAo
4/s1600/WP_20140502_17_14_51_Pro.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The big job was coming together as team, and you guys did that” – Joseph Patton&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of the two teams that actually flew today, one was Team Murphy. Their flight was welcomed with applause. It was very heavy winds and basic flight control was very difficult. Thankfully they made it down in one piece. Murphy retrieved some very good images from this flight and look very prepared for the official competition. They also received two standing ovations for Rijesh’s piloting, mostly because there were no seats. But still a standing ovation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Canadian Competition After a Lovely Little Dip</title>
      <link>http://uaarg.com/2014/05/01/canadian-competition-after-lovely/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://uaarg.com/2014/05/01/canadian-competition-after-lovely</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So after a very lengthy period of not posting, it is time for Canadian Competition again. Right now we are on our way to Southport, Manitoba, rocking to skipping music tracks and testing electrical components. So why are we testing components, well yesterday we decided to let the plane take a dip at the pond adjacent to our flying field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-tQGKtS5-m6g/U2LnVe-p7pI/AAAAAAAAAOU/PRyzpM6u7xg/s1
600/lRpg0GdnpHArknGAKjeGTiGtdKk7QWgO2wwusmnrIWA.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-tQGKtS5-m6g/U2LnVe-p7pI/AAAAAAAAAOU/PRyzpM6u7x
g/s1600/lRpg0GdnpHArknGAKjeGTiGtdKk7QWgO2wwusmnrIWA.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rijesh and Mark pulling the plane out of the pond&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a fun adventure pulling this fellow out of the lake. We were experiencing intermittent Radio Control(RC) loss while in the air. Some on ground range testing would have been wise, but fortune favours the bold. Apparently not. The plane lost RC and crashed into the lake. Our Airframe is in fairly decent shape. The landing gear is a goner but the plane took the crash well. Our Avionics box filled with itself up with water. We have two switching voltage regulators that were built as a capstone project, and thankfully those shorted and blew up fairly quickly. Our telemetry radio has a few scorch marks on it, so it is probably pushing up daisies. Apart from that the rest of the electronics seem fine. Contrary to popular belief water isn’t that extensively damaging to circuitry. As long as the water is not filled with excessive dissolved solvents the water actually acts as an insulator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Mark’s steadfast work, we have a second airframe ready to go. We should be able to remake the Avionics box, with a few adjustments to accommodate a new radio and possibly and new autopilot board. Our current Autopilot board uses something called a PPM encoder which takes the signals from all the channels of the RC receiver and converts it into a single pulse signal. If this is fried we may or may not decide to transition to a Lisa/M 2 autopilot board. This board has a built in receiver. Using this board will require us to reconfigure our autopilot software. Since we are not using any autopilot stabilized flight, this would not actually benefit us. At this competition, however, we were only planning on flying the plane via RC. The original autopilot board without the ppm encoder will still allow us to fly, take photos, geo-reference images, and monitor the plane’s telemetry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking back it seems like our intermittent RC issues may have been due to a metal cowl we added to the plane. We have eliminated faulty hardware and brown outs as possible causes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year, we are bringing a second team to the competition – Team Murphy. They’re a subgroup of UAARG composed of fourth year students designing a small lightweight UAV for their capstone project. All fourth year engineering students take part in a yearlong project, where they apply what they have learned from a variety of their courses. They had some very promising results in there test flight yesterday. They managed to retrieve very clear images and find some targets we set up on the ground, giving some good data for the georeferencing part of their system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The van was just now filled with everyone on a laptop coding and working away on something or another, save the driver.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Jekyll Incorporated Features</title>
      <link>http://uaarg.com/2013/10/08/incorporated/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://uaarg.com/2013/10/08/incorporated</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Incorporated provides a great typography, responsive design, author details, semantic markup and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can set customize post covers, and other things directly in the post front matter:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class='highlight'&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class='yaml'&gt;&lt;span class='l-Scalar-Plain'&gt;layout&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='p-Indicator'&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='l-Scalar-Plain'&gt;post&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class='l-Scalar-Plain'&gt;title&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='p-Indicator'&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='l-Scalar-Plain'&gt;Jekyll Incorporated Features&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class='l-Scalar-Plain'&gt;subtitle&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='p-Indicator'&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='s'&gt;&amp;quot;What&amp;#39;s&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='nv'&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='s'&gt;in&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='nv'&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='s'&gt;the&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='nv'&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='s'&gt;box&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class='c1'&gt;# Setup post cover image in /images/&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class='l-Scalar-Plain'&gt;cover_image&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='p-Indicator'&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='l-Scalar-Plain'&gt;blog-cover.jpg&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class='l-Scalar-Plain'&gt;excerpt&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='p-Indicator'&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='s'&gt;&amp;quot;Incorporated&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='nv'&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='s'&gt;provides&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='nv'&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='s'&gt;a&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='nv'&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='s'&gt;great&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='nv'&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='s'&gt;typography,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='nv'&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='s'&gt;responsive&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='nv'&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='s'&gt;design,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='nv'&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='s'&gt;author&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='nv'&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='s'&gt;details,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='nv'&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='s'&gt;semantic&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='nv'&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='s'&gt;markup&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='nv'&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='s'&gt;and&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='nv'&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='s'&gt;more.&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class='c1'&gt;# Author details, including Google Plus authorship&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class='l-Scalar-Plain'&gt;author&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='p-Indicator'&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class='l-Scalar-Plain'&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='p-Indicator'&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='l-Scalar-Plain'&gt;Karri Saarinen&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class='l-Scalar-Plain'&gt;twitter&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='p-Indicator'&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='l-Scalar-Plain'&gt;karrisaarinen&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class='l-Scalar-Plain'&gt;gplus&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='p-Indicator'&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='l-Scalar-Plain'&gt;100687498195339762535&lt;/span&gt; 
  &lt;span class='l-Scalar-Plain'&gt;bio&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='p-Indicator'&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='l-Scalar-Plain'&gt;Co-founder, Design&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class='l-Scalar-Plain'&gt;image&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='p-Indicator'&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='l-Scalar-Plain'&gt;ks.jpg&lt;/span&gt;
  
&lt;span class='c1'&gt;# Keep it as draft, not published in index.html or feed.xml&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class='l-Scalar-Plain'&gt;draft&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='p-Indicator'&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='l-Scalar-Plain'&gt;false&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;configurable__code_snipped_highlighting&quot;&gt;Configurable &amp;amp; Code Snipped Highlighting&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;/assets/stylesheets/main.scss:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class='highlight'&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class='scss'&gt;&lt;span class='cm'&gt;/* Bodytext font */&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class='nv'&gt;$font&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='o'&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='s2'&gt;&amp;quot;Droid Sans&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='o'&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='s2'&gt;&amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='o'&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='n'&gt;Helvetica&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='o'&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='n'&gt;Arial&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='o'&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='no'&gt;sans-serif&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='p'&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class='cm'&gt;/* Font for headings */&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class='nv'&gt;$fontheadings&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='o'&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='s2'&gt;&amp;quot;Droid Sans&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='o'&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='s2'&gt;&amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='o'&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='n'&gt;Helvetica&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='o'&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='n'&gt;Arial&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='o'&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='no'&gt;sans-serif&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='p'&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class='cm'&gt;/* Text colors */&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class='nv'&gt;$text&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='o'&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='mh'&gt;#21272d&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='p'&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class='nv'&gt;$textmuted&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='o'&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='mh'&gt;#848484&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='p'&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class='nv'&gt;$accent&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='o'&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='mh'&gt;#2077b2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='p'&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;    
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;config.yml:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class='highlight'&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class='yaml'&gt;&lt;span class='l-Scalar-Plain'&gt;inc&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='p-Indicator'&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class='c1'&gt;# Blog Information&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class='l-Scalar-Plain'&gt;title&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='p-Indicator'&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;        &lt;span class='s'&gt;&amp;quot;Jekyll&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='nv'&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='s'&gt;Incorporated&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class='l-Scalar-Plain'&gt;subtitle&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='p-Indicator'&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;     &lt;span class='s'&gt;&amp;quot;Modern&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='nv'&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='s'&gt;Jekyll&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='nv'&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='s'&gt;based&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='nv'&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='s'&gt;blog&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='nv'&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='s'&gt;for&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='nv'&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='s'&gt;companies&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class='l-Scalar-Plain'&gt;cover_image&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='p-Indicator'&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;  &lt;span class='l-Scalar-Plain'&gt;blog-cover.jpg&lt;/span&gt;
  
  &lt;span class='c1'&gt;# Company information&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class='l-Scalar-Plain'&gt;company&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='p-Indicator'&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;      &lt;span class='l-Scalar-Plain'&gt;Incorporated&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class='l-Scalar-Plain'&gt;url&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='p-Indicator'&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;          &lt;span class='l-Scalar-Plain'&gt;http://incorporated.sendtoinc.com/&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class='l-Scalar-Plain'&gt;facebook&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='p-Indicator'&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;     &lt;span class='l-Scalar-Plain'&gt;sendtoinc&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class='l-Scalar-Plain'&gt;twitter&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='p-Indicator'&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;      &lt;span class='l-Scalar-Plain'&gt;sendtoinc&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class='l-Scalar-Plain'&gt;about_link&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='p-Indicator'&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;   &lt;span class='l-Scalar-Plain'&gt;https://sendtoinc.com/about/&lt;/span&gt;
  
  &lt;span class='c1'&gt;# Product Information&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class='l-Scalar-Plain'&gt;product_link&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='p-Indicator'&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class='l-Scalar-Plain'&gt;http://incorporated.sendtoinc.com/&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class='l-Scalar-Plain'&gt;tagline&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='p-Indicator'&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;      &lt;span class='s'&gt;&amp;quot;Get&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='nv'&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='s'&gt;a&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='nv'&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='s'&gt;modern&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='nv'&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='s'&gt;blog&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='nv'&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='s'&gt;for&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='nv'&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='s'&gt;your&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='nv'&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='s'&gt;company&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
  
  &lt;span class='c1'&gt;# Comments&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class='l-Scalar-Plain'&gt;disqus&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='p-Indicator'&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class='c1'&gt;# Eg. &amp;quot;exampleblog&amp;quot; Set to false to disable comments&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class='l-Scalar-Plain'&gt;shortname&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='p-Indicator'&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;  &lt;span class='l-Scalar-Plain'&gt;false&lt;/span&gt;
  
  
  &lt;span class='c1'&gt;# Sharing settings&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class='l-Scalar-Plain'&gt;sharing&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='p-Indicator'&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class='l-Scalar-Plain'&gt;twitter&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='p-Indicator'&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;    &lt;span class='l-Scalar-Plain'&gt;false&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class='l-Scalar-Plain'&gt;facebook&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='p-Indicator'&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;   &lt;span class='l-Scalar-Plain'&gt;false&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class='l-Scalar-Plain'&gt;gplus&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='p-Indicator'&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;      &lt;span class='l-Scalar-Plain'&gt;false&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class='l-Scalar-Plain'&gt;hn&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='p-Indicator'&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;         &lt;span class='l-Scalar-Plain'&gt;false&lt;/span&gt;
    
  
 &lt;span class='c1'&gt;# Analytics     &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class='l-Scalar-Plain'&gt;analytics&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='p-Indicator'&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class='l-Scalar-Plain'&gt;google&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='p-Indicator'&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; 
      &lt;span class='c1'&gt;# eg. &amp;#39;UA-123-12&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class='l-Scalar-Plain'&gt;id&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='p-Indicator'&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;       &lt;span class='l-Scalar-Plain'&gt;false&lt;/span&gt;    
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Zoomable images&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class='full zoomable'&gt;&lt;img src='/images/incorporated.jpg' /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Awesome quotes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Effective companies tend to communicate more, their people are curious and they have opinions”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned for updates.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>AUVSI SUAS Competition part 2</title>
      <link>http://uaarg.com/2013/06/22/auvsi-suas-competition-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://uaarg.com/2013/06/22/auvsi-suas-competition-part-2</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s been an eventful, stressful, and exciting few days for us at the AUVSI SUAS competition; we’ve finally finished with all things competition and are totally ready to get some much-needed sleep. We placed 23rd overall out of a total of 33 teams at the competition. We received a $400 cash prize, and our oral presentation scored fairly high at a position of 15th, beating the first place team who got 18th.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Day one of the competition was mostly getting setup and tested to be certified to fly. As we started the day, we were dedicated mostly to our last minute preparations to our Flight Readiness Review. The FRR was the oral presentation component of the competition; we were required to go over an overview of our system, our safety measures, and the results of our systems testing. In the end, we were able to prepare a nice, organized 15 minute presentation that closely followed the requirements for the review.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another crucial task on day one was the setup of the autopilot system; this included setting up the failsafes and defining the search areas and boundaries of the field. One component of the competition was navigating the plane through a series of waypoints, and so these also had to be plotted. As we did not feel comfortable flying in fully autonomous mode, our plan was to have Cameron (our safety pilot) navigate using stabilized flight mode through these waypoints, then fly a pattern over the search area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Day two was when flights started. We arrived early in the morning to set up our system and make small improvements. T here were, of course, various issues that popped up throughout the day. Under the heat, the epoxy glue holding the elevators melted, and we had to quickly remove and repair the elevators. We also worked on creating a better image geolocation algorithm; throughout the day, we were in a rush to finish things because we weren’t certain how long the other teams would take for their flights and when we would be up for ours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At around 5:00 PM on day two after around 23 teams had flown, they announced that the remaining teams would fly the next day and that we were in the first four.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We finally received our chance to go out and fly on Saturday. Each team was given one chance to complete a mission flight time of 40 minutes. As soon as we arrived at the field we set up our system for our flight. Somewhere within the frantic activities of assembling the plane and taking it out to the flight area, the XTend transmitter lost it’s ability to transmit past 10 meters. We made our way out onto the air strip, setup the ground and imaging stations, the mission time started, and we commenced our pre-flight checks, only to discover the fault in the XTend radio. 17 minutes and 33 seconds into the mission time, Cameron requested a timeout, which was granted. Arshad, Sheldon, and Cameron took off to the nearby St Mary’s College campus to see what was wrong with the radio without interfering with other team’s radio transmissions. After much troubleshooting and testing, the problem was diagnosed: the RF cable connector between the Xtend radio and the antenna was causing attenuation, so was swapped out with a new XTend module which has an RP-SMA connector to allow a direct antenna, foregoing the problem-ridden cable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/c6qbwdu5iiFHaBlquTs4D0np4MUH2bPimM
ygCXWYeUdvRJ5eUrD9wT9JI0-l8kXbLr1G9Hn8M4hdWUtyIA_nn3s52IvDaAHmmJGvUKffalUW3jBK
Hi6iC0z8jg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/c6qbwdu5iiFHaBlquTs4D0np4MUH2bPimMygCX
WYeUdvRJ5eUrD9wT9JI0-l8kXbLr1G9Hn8M4hdWUtyIA_nn3s52IvDaAHmmJGvUKffalUW3jBKHi6i
C0z8jg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The XTend radio we’ve been using reliably for many months&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a remaining mission time of 22 minutes, we hustled out into the field for our second flight. We soon got the entire system up and running: telemetry, R/C, and Wi-Fi links were all functional at the beginning of the flight, and images were being successfully transferred and displayed. However, immediately upon taking off we noticed that the elevator neutral was much too far down. This was because we had to replace it the previous day since the epoxy holding the elevators together softened up in the heat and we obviously mis-estimated the proper neutral. After landing and adjusting the servo positions, we took off to make the most of our remaining 12 minutes of flight time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During this flight, we noticed that images were coming in at a very sporadic rate, and that only a limited number of images were being transferred. Most of these images were of locations near the runway, and none of them contained a target. The Wi-Fi connection from the onboard Pandaboard to the ground imaging computer was spotty all throughout the flight, which caused certain photos to fail to transfer. After our landing, we tried to transfer the images directly from the Pandaboard to our ground station, but there was too little time to do so and to obtain the target information for the judges; in the end, we handed in a blank target sheet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh6.googleusercontent.com
/bbySGs9VKmkJfbRzTMC3SqoSPzIXy7O80tMkXHebYRC8_QTsx60xCJdfd-
PuYMjyy2CLESZhapp0WMaTvx9PJi9boU8Hw11ZmKIizi_0hVqrnUJpxLnlwAIKMw&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our flight path including elevation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With all the problems with the flight and the different parts of the plane, we still got some amazing data: alot of the search area was covered by Cameron’s impeccable piloting, and a lot of the targets were captured by the plane. GPS and altitude of the plane were recorded beautifully by paparazzi, and we were able to export the data to google earth, where we were treated with a 3D model of the planes path around the flight area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-sIVkX39wzew/UcZxez5oIHI/AAAAAAAAAI
o/VjpBeLi0hAs/s1600/507.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-sIVkX39wzew/UcZxez5oIHI/AAAAAAAAAIo/VjpBeLi0hA
s/s320/507.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cross with I&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-raRTxUE9jRA/UcZxf6hkZaI/AAAAAAAAAJ
Q/XiI1KpNQd54/s1600/517.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-raRTxUE9jRA/UcZxf6hkZaI/AAAAAAAAAJQ/XiI1KpNQd5
4/s320/517.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pop up target?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-iqGH8Vga0_4/UcZxgtCJrAI/AAAAAAAAAJ
o/1nKRTn26t8o/s1600/543.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-iqGH8Vga0_4/UcZxgtCJrAI/AAAAAAAAAJo/1nKRTn26t8
o/s320/543.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blue Star with 0&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-yLUAcsDdais/UcZxhL96fnI/AAAAAAAAAJ
8/vsRvjhlqEFw/s1600/560.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-yLUAcsDdais/UcZxhL96fnI/AAAAAAAAAJ8/vsRvjhlqEF
w/s320/560.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or is this the pop up target?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-nG20f_8G6vE/UcZxh7Ga4lI/AAAAAAAAAK
c/5BHvQWEG2XY/s1600/597.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-nG20f_8G6vE/UcZxh7Ga4lI/AAAAAAAAAKc/5BHvQWEG2X
Y/s320/597.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quarter Circle with a B&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-N-L3jKwEnOo/UcZxkdxtt1I/AAAAAAAAAL
o/kfzBE8k8HVI/s1600/704.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-N-L3jKwEnOo/UcZxkdxtt1I/AAAAAAAAALo/kfzBE8k8HV
I/s320/704.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;White Sqare with T&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-IbqZ3-Bsc-M/UcZxlNDUJeI/AAAAAAAAAM
I/P0wEzj8BzcI/s1600/753.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-IbqZ3-Bsc-M/UcZxlNDUJeI/AAAAAAAAAMI/P0wEzj8Bzc
I/s320/753.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rectangle with N&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-FMNxd5LLpqE/UcZxlpgDwsI/AAAAAAAAAM
c/Ekae_9bPb5E/s1600/850.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-FMNxd5LLpqE/UcZxlpgDwsI/AAAAAAAAAMc/Ekae_9bPb5
E/s320/850.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Circle&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And here are what some of these targets look like on the ground:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-9LMy77tWKB
w/UcX_F0QwJgI/AAAAAAAAI6A/fIl_SZa5jzY/w680-h510-no/IMG_20130622_130652.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-9LMy77tWKBw/UcX_F0QwJgI/AAAAAAAAI6A/fIl_SZa5jz
Y/w680-h510-no/IMG_20130622_130652.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-6dJdjSJ2Ilw/UcX-40XCe_I/AAAAAAAAI5o/tOmw6JmV-
cg/w680-h510-no/IMG_20130622_130639.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-6dJdjSJ2Ilw/UcX-40XCe_I/AAAAAAAAI5o/tOmw6JmV-
cg/w680-h510-no/IMG_20130622_130639.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-c4ps4GK9wY
Q/UcX_mk4xa6I/AAAAAAAAI6w/8HCd_QNNw94/w737-h553-no/IMG_20130622_130716.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-c4ps4GK9wYQ/UcX_mk4xa6I/AAAAAAAAI6w/8HCd_QNNw9
4/w737-h553-no/IMG_20130622_130716.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We still need to take a closer look at our GPS data to see how accurately we might have located these targets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all, although we didn’t perform as well as we wanted to at this competition we believe that we’ve made significant progress this year and are looking forward to further development over the summer and through 2013-2014 for next year’s competitions. We’ll continue to work on stuff, seek new members, and update this blog as we rise to meet the many more challenges that are sure to come.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>AUVSI SUAS Competition</title>
      <link>http://uaarg.com/2013/06/19/auvsi-suas-competition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://uaarg.com/2013/06/19/auvsi-suas-competition</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;And here we go again… competition #2: the Association for Unmanned Vehicle Systems International (AUVSI) Student Unmanned Aerial Systems (SUAS) competition. This competition is in Maryland in the US.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learning from our trip to Quebec, we arrived at the airport 4 hours early this time. Because of this, and because the airport was practically empty - only overnight flights were left - baggage check in went smoothly. Our crates were 68 and 70 pounds with the limit being 70. Some of our checked luggage was 48 and 49 pounds, with the limit (to avoid a fee) being 50. We had to show Air Canada their own rules on maximum luggage size though. Before we did this, they were telling us the maximum sizes to avoid the oversize fee as if those were the absolute limits. They were very friendly and helpful though, especially considering our complex situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re currently waiting for our flight which should leave at 1:00 am. Hopefully we’ll get sleep in the air since by the time we get to Washington, it’ll be 10:00 AM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-vGquG8A2Zac/UcFQ6
AAcCGI/AAAAAAAAAHs/VplIdEd0PIo/s1600/IMG_20130618_235938.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-vGquG8A2Zac/UcFQ6AAcCGI/AAAAAAAAAHs/VplIdEd0PI
o/s1600/IMG_20130618_235938.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cindy and Arshad waiting at the airport&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for technical aspects, we’ve been working hard on our system for the past month and a half. We did lots of flight testing, but damaged the plane twice and spent a lot of time trying to get neutral IMU values. We’ve fixed our plane and have relatively reliable stabilized flight, but haven’t achieved fully autonomous flight yet. As for imaging, we’ve made a lot of progress. Images are now reliably transferred over FTP and the ground imaging GUI can load them up as they come in. We still need to work on our geo-referencing algorithm. Pictures taken during flight testing showed that this can be off by over 50 meters. We’ll be working on this over the next day or two as well as enabling telemetry over Wi-Fi so that we can show off our redundant link software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-Ll9ed925-cE/UcFKjoF6SuI/AAAAAAAAAHc/2AXYew-
vwsA/s1600/IMG_20130516_202053.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-Ll9ed925-cE/UcFKjoF6SuI/AAAAAAAAAHc/2AXYew-
vwsA/s1600/IMG_20130516_202053.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The damage to our motor after a failed takeoff&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-NfO_fVot3jw/UcFKg
SgkeVI/AAAAAAAAAHU/Ez73iz5k99U/s1600/IMG_20130611_203803.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-NfO_fVot3jw/UcFKgSgkeVI/AAAAAAAAAHU/Ez73iz5k99
U/s1600/IMG_20130611_203803.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr. Duncan Elliott holding the plane while testing the camera configuration&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re looking forward to arriving in Maryland (and the comfy beds in our hotel) as well as the competition itself. Expect a new post around once a day until the competition is done. Also, feel free to leave comments below, ask questions, or initiate any other type of discussion. We’d love to hear who’s reading this blog and are able to post specific content based on what you’re interested in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-iZkoDRO8GhI/UcFRJ
JNX0nI/AAAAAAAAAH0/o1zJpnunRG4/s1600/IMG_20130618_235933.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-iZkoDRO8GhI/UcFRJJNX0nI/AAAAAAAAAH0/o1zJpnunRG
4/s1600/IMG_20130618_235933.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Emmanuel looking forward to the hotel in Maryland&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Competition Flight 2 - Day 3 - USC UAV Competition</title>
      <link>http://uaarg.com/2013/05/06/day-3-usc-uav/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://uaarg.com/2013/05/06/day-3-usc-uav</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This morning, we were able to get out onto the field right away and perform a range test. Soon afterwards, we began our second competition flight. We brought a second router for this flight in order to set up a connection to a computer that would display the GCS to the pilot, in an attempt to perform stabilized flight out of the line of sight and thereby expand our search area. The plane’s takeoff and flight were smooth, and the radio and telemetry links to the plane remained connected throughout.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-_PQtLWAmY2I/UYgt7AMx4II/AAAAAA
AAAGw/VAmeaHt4Idk/s1600/blogp1.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-_PQtLWAmY2I/UYgt7AMx4II/AAAAAAAAAGw/VAmeaHt4Id
k/s1600/blogp1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cameron monitoring the plane down the runway, with the pilot GCS laptop in front&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-wAaa9RlDcpU/UYguaxwgDdI/AAAAAAAAAG4/3e-
QB_V31E4/s1600/blogp2.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, almost immediately after takeoff, we noticed that the wi-fi connection between the Pandaboard and the ground imaging laptop was extremely weak, and at one point, even disconnected entirely. This meant that we were only able to wirelessly transfer the first few photos taken by the plane. We continued with the flight because it was still possible to land and make a direct wired connection afterwards to transfer the images taken. A few of us hypothesized that there was some interference between the two routers, but it was only after the plane landed that we discovered that the new router was using the _ exact same frequency _ as the router used for the imaging despite being set to auto select an unused frequency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-wAaa9RlDcpU/UYguaxwgDdI/AAAAAA
AAAG8/cs8iBFYoD1g/s1600/blogp2.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-wAaa9RlDcpU/UYguaxwgDdI/AAAAAAAAAG8/cs8iBFYoD1
g/s1600/blogp2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking at the targets at the imaging station&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite this, we were still able to get all the images that the plane took. Here are a few:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-U7TwmsXP0tQ/UYgswg9kk0I/AAAAAA
AAAGo/OjvLR9HUsS4/s1600/blogp3.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-U7TwmsXP0tQ/UYgswg9kk0I/AAAAAAAAAGo/OjvLR9HUsS
4/s1600/blogp3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-ZrN4_wKeMJ4/UYgu14BCDVI/AAAAAA
AAAHE/sUdWJaMTp3U/s1600/blogp4.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-ZrN4_wKeMJ4/UYgu14BCDVI/AAAAAAAAAHE/sUdWJaMTp3
U/s1600/blogp4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see, there was no possibility of discerning targets from any of these blurry photos. This was because we had made another critical mistake: we had taken out the working camera used for yesterday’s flight and replaced it with the other identical but unfocused camera. Therefore, during this flight, we were unable to identify any targets. With the wind picking up and dark clouds approaching, competition flights ended during the morning, and with that went our last chance to improve on yesterday’s score.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The afternoon’s activities were a welcome break. Most of this time was taken up by the Mini-expo, which was a chance for all of the teams to set up their systems to show to the public, sponsors, and other competitors, and to go around and talk to the other teams. Cameron tried to add telemetry over Wi-Fi functionality to the Panda Board in order to show a proper demo of his redundant link system, but there were problems setting it up. Nevertheless, we were able to gather some interesting information about the other teams’ operations. We also got a chance to look inside the unmanned aircraft MISKAM at its systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After packing up our aircraft and other supplies, we headed to the final banquet for acknowledgments, congratulations, and finally the announcement of results. All of the teams that were able to get airborne were also able to get target information. It turned out for us that out of the three targets we identified the previous day, only two were correctly georeferenced. Every other team obtained more targets than we did, mainly by virtue of performing more than one flight with collection of target data. It seemed that correctly obtaining GPS coordinates was a problem for many teams; even the top team, VAMUDeS, had incorrect GPS information for about a third of their 30 targets. We were glad to still receive a $500 cash prize; we also obtained files with the correct target information and locations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One bonus during this trip was our reception of media coverage. A reporter from Radio-Canada came to the airport yesterday to do a news story on the competition, and she interviewed- us about our systems and out performance during our first flight. Our team ended up receiving the majority of the coverage of the news story; a link to it can be found &lt;a href=&quot;http://www
.radio-canada.ca/regions/saguenay-lac/2013/05/04/004-drone-competition-
universitaire-alma.shtml&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-4m1biray2KY/UYgsdrKwEuI/AAAA
AAAAAGg/kCLTHyERX5M/s1600/IMG_0448.JPG&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-4m1biray2KY/UYgsdrKwEuI/AAAAAAAAAGg/kCLTHyERX5
M/s1600/IMG_0448.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Demonstrating our ground control station to the RDI reporters&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alma was an incredibly hospitable place, and we had a lot of fun during the competition despite encountering some pretty major obstacles. There are many things for us to reflect on for the next competition, and an enormous list of things for us to work on, including a better systems presentation, major fixes for the ground imaging software, and more detailed pre-flight checklists. This Thursday, we will be having a meeting at which we can work on these and plan the next one and a half months until the AUVSI competition. Stay tuned for more updates then.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-3awgW3f39Uw/UYgrxEffDsI/AAAA
AAAAAGY/7bdzj71LQRI/s1600/IMG_0945.JPG&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-3awgW3f39Uw/UYgrxEffDsI/AAAAAAAAAGY/7bdzj71LQR
I/s1600/IMG_0945.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;L to R: Cindy Xiao, Arshad Husain, Sheldon Marquis, Cameron Lee, Emmanuel Odeke&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Competition Flight 1 - Day 2 - USC UAV Competition</title>
      <link>http://uaarg.com/2013/05/04/day-2-usc-uav/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://uaarg.com/2013/05/04/day-2-usc-uav</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After all of the troubles yesterday, today has been a breath of fresh air so far. We got up at 6:30 AM for breakfast at 7:00 AM and start of round 1 flights at 8:00 AM. Of the ten teams, we’re last on the list to fly, so we flew at around 1:00 pm. With the servos now adjusted properly (thanks to a member from team VAMUdeS for helping with this), we had a great manual takeoff, very stable flight, and even flew in auto1 (stabilized) flight for extended periods of time. We were also able to take pictures and start looking for targets. During our 30 minute flight block, we actually took off and landed twice. During the first flight we lost our telemetry link to the autopilot during takeoff, but it worked great during the second flight, so we’re not sure what went wrong. Also, we lost connection to the on-board computer while in the air, but re-acquired it after the plane came closer to the ground station. We were able to view and look for targets, although our ground imaging software wasn’t loading the new pictures properly, so we did this manually using an image viewer. After our 30 minute flight period, we had issues with the FTP transfer so copied the remaining images over via USB. We then filled out our target sheet with the three targets we found and submitted it to the judges (pictures of these targets to be added after the competition is over).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-zbNikZIGzo8/UYV3A
yHsRbI/AAAAAAAAAGE/2VWf3jwtVIQ/s1600/IMG_20130504_130349.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-zbNikZIGzo8/UYV3AyHsRbI/AAAAAAAAAGE/2VWf3jwtVI
Q/s1600/IMG_20130504_130349.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cindy Xiao looking for targets during the flight&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A portion of our flight&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we consider this flight a success and are working hard to make our next one even better. There are three things we’re working on:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get the FTP connection working reliable. As of this blog post, we actually think we’ve got this finished.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Set up a second autopilot GCS for the pilot to view the plane on a map while flying in stabilized mode. This should let us fly further away from the takeoff area to cover a larger search area. As of this post, the setup has been done, but the decision as to whether we’ll actually fly further away will be made during out phase 2 flight tomorrow.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Fix the ground imaging station software so that we can load and view pictures. Or, if this proves too difficult, create a new, simple program that will convert the UTM location data into lat and long data automatically.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve been informed that the rest of phase 2 will start tomorrow, so that’s when we’ll be flying next. this gives us the opportunity to fix our issues and get a good night of sleep. As long as we don’t encounter any unexpected issues, tomorrow should be a great day.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Setup and Flight Testing - Day 1 - USC UAV Competition</title>
      <link>http://uaarg.com/2013/05/03/usc-uav/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://uaarg.com/2013/05/03/usc-uav</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The morning today was mostly dedicated to assembly and preparation of systems, our safety briefing, and our systems presentation. The preparation for the presentation was done in a rush, and we did not go over the technical details of our systems and our team’s project management as much as we would have liked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We ran into a host of unexpected issues almost as soon as we finished assembling our plane and avionics box; as a result, it took a good part of the day to successfully receive and transmit data from the plane and demonstrate our failsafes in order to pass our flight readiness reviews and be cleared for flight tests. First, when we went to do our flight readiness review, none of our kill switches worked – because the lack of GPS was already killing the plane, but we didn’t realize this until later. Then there was a bad connection in the IMU followed by a mysterious issue with one of the power supplies within the plane cutting out. We don’t know yet whether this was a short or some other cause, because when we disassembled the avionics box to replace the power supply, it started working again and has been fine since.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once we got to the field, we were able to perform a calibration of our IMU, a demonstration of our failsafes, and a successful manual flight with transmission of telemetry data. The flight, however, was not smooth; the plane’s ascent was choppy, and the pilot (Cameron was barely able to control it). After three failed landing attempts – one where the plane nearly exited the flight area while at only 10 m, we eventually landed the plane with no damage. We determined that the cause of this brutal flight was twofold: the deflection of the elevator and aileron control surfaces was much too too high (the deflections in these reached their maximums at only 50% input), and the COG was a little bit tail-heavy. We were easily able to fix both of these issues and should be able to fly properly tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Work on imaging systems has also been encountering numerous issues, including problems with wi-fi connection of the imaging computer to the PandaBoard, offsets returned by ground imaging target selection algorithm too large to be reasonable, and issues with loading images and data from watched directories. As we now have basic flight functionality, we plan to focus most of our work tomorrow on imaging.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pictures and Video Below&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-l3bZsE5RBoc/UYVyPHGkHTI/AAAAA
AAAAFc/vhnKl0dqUVM/s1600/P5030008.JPG&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-l3bZsE5RBoc/UYVyPHGkHTI/AAAAAAAAAFc/vhnKl0dqUV
M/s640/P5030008.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-xy4oX1RX7KQ/UYVyQTli6eI/AAAAA
AAAAFk/E36TXdRbEFU/s1600/P5030010.JPG&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-xy4oX1RX7KQ/UYVyQTli6eI/AAAAAAAAAFk/E36TXdRbEF
U/s640/P5030010.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-4rCJfPKLrP8/UYVySa5nalI/AAAAA
AAAAFs/N-3_RVnMW9c/s1600/P5030032.JPG&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-4rCJfPKLrP8/UYVySa5nalI/AAAAAAAAAFs/N-3_RVnMW9
c/s640/P5030032.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-qlbZHY7NBTs/UYVyThrvSnI/AAAAA
AAAAF0/IW4T2qEA4Jk/s1600/P5030033.JPG&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-qlbZHY7NBTs/UYVyThrvSnI/AAAAAAAAAF0/IW4T2qEA4J
k/s640/P5030033.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 0 - Unmanned Systems Canada UAV Competition</title>
      <link>http://uaarg.com/2013/05/02/unmanned-systems-canada-uav/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://uaarg.com/2013/05/02/unmanned-systems-canada-uav</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Good news - we have just arrived in Alma, Quebec for the Unmanned Systems Canada Student UAV Competition. The past few days leading up to competition have been both hectic and tiring as we struggled to get systems in good working order, to pack our plane and tools, and to rest up to be in good traveling shape.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-NZW6qhOeaO8/UYM
88eLJvbI/AAAAAAAAAE8/lNWhMSbYyd4/s1600/IMG_20130501_162451_1.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-NZW6qhOeaO8/UYM88eLJvbI/AAAAAAAAAE8/lNWhMSbYyd
4/s1600/IMG_20130501_162451_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our plane disassembled and packed in its crate&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We met at the airport this morning at 4:30am and promptly discovered that one and a half hours was not enough to make it to the gate at a comfortable time for our 6am flight. Re-packing our spare items into checked baggage and processing our two large oversized crates were both extremely time-consuming, and we just made it in time for boarding. Fortunately, the remainder of our trip by air to Montreal went well, and we were able to drop off our crates to be shipped and promptly get our rental car.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-CNrB7PTju2E/UYM9M
J6LUbI/AAAAAAAAAFE/DRcvDHN9x6Y/s1600/IMG_20130502_054313.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-CNrB7PTju2E/UYM9MJ6LUbI/AAAAAAAAAFE/DRcvDHN9x6
Y/s1600/IMG_20130502_054313.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cameron and Sheldon feeling optimistic&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-_mLDx3TsYJE/UYM9TNgca-I/AAAAAAAAAFM/tV-
ybIt3YYo/s1600/IMG_20130502_144429.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-_mLDx3TsYJE/UYM9TNgca-I/AAAAAAAAAFM/tV-
ybIt3YYo/s1600/IMG_20130502_144429.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our crates, finally arrived at Montreal&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the major things that we got done during the trip was creating a complete flight plan specific to the airfield in Alma. This included defining the perimeter of the competition field in our autopilot software, determining the flight altitude, and creating takeoff and landing waypoints. We also worked on refining the ground station imaging system and on our Technical Presentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow, we perform both our Technical Presentation and Flight Readiness Reviews, both major contributors to our overall score. These are critical for giving judges an overview of our systems and for ensuring flight safety prior to the first day of competition flight on Saturday.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Redundant Communication - An Improvement to Paparazzi</title>
      <link>http://uaarg.com/2013/04/21/redundant-communication-improvement-to/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://uaarg.com/2013/04/21/redundant-communication-improvement-to</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a special post, written to describe the redundant communication project being worked on by myself - Cameron Lee - current president of UAARG. The goal of this project is to allow multiple radio modems or other links be used between the aircraft and the ground station in a redundant fashion so that even if one link is lost, communication can be maintained.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far, the plane to ground component has been created and tested. This post describes how to use it and how it works. The code can be viewed or downloaded from github:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/uaarg/paparazzi/tree/redundant_comms&quot;&gt;https://github.com/uaarg/paparazzi/tree/redundant_comms&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;video&quot;&gt;Video&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following video is a demonstration of the system working and the interface that lets you monitor links. The sections below discuss the details more thoroughly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Redundant Link Demonstration for Papparazzi Autopilot&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;design&quot;&gt;Design&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll assume that the reader is somewhat familiar with how the ground segment of Paparazzi currently works. However, this information can be found on the wiki, here: &lt;a href=&quot;http://paparazzi.enac.fr/wiki/Overview#System_Architecture&quot;&gt;http://paparazzi.enac.fr/wiki/Overview#System_Architecture&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a block diagram showing how the plane talks to the various ground segment programs (also known as agents):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-8-YENO6LcN
s/UXMRpkJlx1I/AAAAAAAAEZQ/Z3XDrJCRzQs/s1600/Normal+Communication+Layout.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-8-YENO6LcNs/UXMRpkJlx1I/AAAAAAAAEZQ/Z3XDrJCRzQ
s/s400/Normal+Communication+Layout.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paparazzi Ground Segment&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ivy bus lets the programs talk to each other through the use of short messages. The direction of the coloured arrows is key since it shows the main flow of these messages. Next we have a block diagram of the redundant link system:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-nx_p90B7FU4/UXMddbJ_gEI/AAAAAAAAEZg/qnbrS-
bS3l0/s1600/Redundant+Communication+Layout.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-nx_p90B7FU4/UXMddbJ_gEI/AAAAAAAAEZg/qnbrS-
bS3l0/s640/Redundant+Communication+Layout.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paparazzi Ground Segment with Redundant Links&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here we can see a new agent, the Link Combiner. We also see multiple occurrences of the Link agent. When operating in redundant mode, each occurrence of Link transmits the data it receives from the plane to the Link Combiner instead of the Server. It does this by transmitting the received telemetry messages within the TELEMETRY_MESSAGE message which the Server doesn’t listen to. The Link Combiner on the other hand does. TELEMETRY_MESSAGE messages are sent by each link and include the id of that link. The Link Combiner listens to all of them and then transmits a single set of messages to the Server with the combined data. This results in the Server and all other ground segment agents (such as Messages and the Real Time Plotter) getting their telemetry data from Link Combiner as if it was coming from a single occurrence of Link.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how_to_use&quot;&gt;How to Use&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to implement redundant links using this code, there are three simple steps to follow:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Connect the hardware - on the airborne side, connect the Tx of the autopilot to multiple radio modems. On the ground side, connect multiple modems as normal (using USB to serial adapters, or whatever).&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Launch a Link agent for each modem. Use two new command line arguments: _ -redlink _ and _ -id. _ The _ -redlink _ flag tells Link that it’s one of multiple links. The _ -id _ flag lets you specify an integer number as the id of that particular link.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Launch the Link Combiner agent.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following screenshot shows a setup with two links, connected to serial ports ttyUSB0 and ttyUSB1, and with id’s 1 and 2:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-4ytdpqXMHa0/UXMlR-
qGkbI/AAAAAAAAEZw/JO959QjWip4/s1600/Screenshot+from+2013-04-15+23_02_27.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-4ytdpqXMHa0/UXMlR-
qGkbI/AAAAAAAAEZw/JO959QjWip4/s640/Screenshot+from+2013-04-15+23_02_27.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Agents Running in a Redundant Link Setup&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;interface&quot;&gt;Interface&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the redundant link system is started (even if only one Link is used), several changes appear in the GCS. This is achieved by the new message LINK_STATUS which is sent by the Link Combiner. These new features are designed to allow closer monitoring and better management of the link(s) between the aircraft and the ground station.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following screenshot clearly shows these changes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-jI
7EMZ_0614/UXMjlc1MoBI/AAAAAAAAEZo/LwOgVQN336o/s1600/Screenshot+from+2013-04-15
+22_59_01.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-jI7EMZ_0614/UXMjlc1MoBI/AAAAAAAAEZo/LwOgVQN336
o/s640/Screenshot+from+2013-04-15+22_59_01.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Firstly, we can see that there is a new page in the notebook named Link. This page contains critical information for each link. More information can easily be added, but for now, it shows the status of the link (just like the main Link status indicator in the strip), the current ping time, and the rate of received messages. So if one link is lost, it’s status indicator will turn red and start counting up just like link 2 in the above screenshot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, we can see that the main Link status indicator that’s located in the strip has been modified slightly. It now shows the ratio of connected links to the total number of links. I.e. 3/4 means that there are four links and one of them has been lost. Furthermore, the indicator will be green if all links are connected, yellow if one or more are lost, and red if all links are lost. Once all links are lost, the indicator will count up just like before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, alerts have been added to the console. Whenever a link is lost or reconnected, a message will appear in the console stating so. Messages also appear when a new link is added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;link_combiner&quot;&gt;Link Combiner&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Link Combiner agent is written in Python. It receives messages from all of the Links (when they’re in redundant mode), and outputs messages to the Server and other ground segment agents. There is a bit involved however since the Server and GCS shouldn’t be sent identical messages. I.e. if the plane sends a message and it’s received successfully by more than one link, then that particular message should only sent by Link Combiner once. This is a somewhat tricky requirement since there is no guarantee that the message will be received by all of the links, and it’s possible that the plane actually sends a second message that’s exactly the same as the first. No extra info (such as a time-stamp or counter) is added to the messages sent from the plane to the ground, so the Link Combiner employs an algorithm to detect duplicate messages. Testing has shown that for typical links, this algorithm performs extremely well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The algorithm gives each link a circular buffer to store the last N messages. When a new message comes in on a particular link, the algorithm first checks if it’s already in that link’s buffer. If it is, then it’s obviously a new message, so its removed from all of the other buffers if it’s in any of them. Then, the message is sent. If the message isn’t already in the link’s buffer, then it’s added to the buffer. After that, all of the other link’s buffers are checked for the message. If it’s in any of them, then the message was already received by another link, so isn’t sent. If it’s not in any of them, then the message is sent. The following flowchart depicts this algorithm:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-G1LYSsliAiY/UXNBjHj9
3PI/AAAAAAAAEaI/hom9cRmd3jI/s1600/Algorithm+Diagram.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-G1LYSsliAiY/UXNBjHj93PI/AAAAAAAAEaI/hom9cRmd3j
I/s640/Algorithm+Diagram.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Algorithm to prevent duplicate messages&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the plane sends various, possibly identical, messages and the links gain and lose connection, there is no guarantee that this algorithm will do a perfect job of filtering out identical and only identical messages. Howeve r, in typical operation, it seems to work very well. And for the application of displaying aircraft data, the occasional missing or duplicate message is acceptable. There are only a few scenarios where the Link Combiner won’t produce perfect results, and they should come up infrequently:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A message will be sent twice if the buffer size is too small to hold all of the messages received from one link between that link receiving the message and another link receiving the identical message. When the second link receives the message that has already been received, if the original isn’t in the buffer anymore, than the algorithm won’t know it’s a duplicate message. This scenario should be considered whenever implementing a redundant link system. Partly because it is the most likely to come up, but also because if it does occur, then all messages will be duplicated. In order to avoid this scenario, you can set the buffer size as a command line argument of Link Combiner. To know what a good value would be, you can observer the Ping time and Rx messages/s of the links in the new Link page of the notebook. Calculate the minimum buffer size by taking the difference between the largest ping time and the smallest ping time and multiplying it by the largest Rx messages/s. Then apply a safety factor when setting the buffer size - 10 times the calculated value should be good.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;A message won’t be sent when it should be if the autopilot sends a message that’s the same as one it already sent (same name and exact same values) AND at least one link was lost between the first message and the second AND the link that’s receiving the second message doesn’t have the first message in it’s buffer still. That’s three conditions. If this happens, then the Link Combiner will see the second message as a duplicate of the first and will skip it. Only this one message will be missed though - it won’t start happening to all messages. Also, the data will have been data that was already received. So if it’s for example the battery voltage message, then it’s not a big deal to miss it. As long as there aren’t links rapidly being lost and gained, then this shouldn’t happen often. Note that as the buffer size is increased, I believe that this becomes more likely to happen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s it. As you can see, this is just the first half to a completely redundant communication system. Once the autopilot is programmed to allow multiple datalink inputs, then a fully redundant, two-directional communications system can be used with Paparazzi. Furthermore, additional features could be added such as the ability to send different messages over different links, or messages at different rates over different links. This could all be configured in the Link page of the notebook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feel free to contact me regarding this at cam.w.lee@gmail.com or through the paparazzi-devel@nongnu.org mailing list (include my name somewhere in the e-mail so that it makes it past my filter).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;- Cameron Lee&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Flying in the Snow</title>
      <link>http://uaarg.com/2013/04/20/flying-in-snow/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://uaarg.com/2013/04/20/flying-in-snow</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s been quite a while since our last post. Many of you can probably guess why… exams. As this semester comes to an end, we’re all extremely busy with studying. Nevertheless, our competitions are approaching fast, so we’re continuing work on our UAV.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-2LL-
VYAcTPk/UXI2-t50P_I/AAAAAAAAAEs/8QTaoLCUIOE/s1600/HPIM5304.JPG&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-2LL-
VYAcTPk/UXI2-t50P_I/AAAAAAAAAEs/8QTaoLCUIOE/s1600/HPIM5304.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adjusting the Skis&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We went flying this Wednesday to test our autopilot. Our objective was to perform a few manual flights to record the necessary data to start configuring the autopilot for our Senior Telemaster Plus. Then, if everything went according to plan, we would attempt stabilized (auto1) flight. Of course, everything didn’t go according to plane. Because we had so many issues, here they are itemized:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Most of the picnic tables were buried in snow, so we had to use one located right next to a pool of water.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The autopilot couldn’t receive a location from our new GPS. In fact, it didn’t receive any data at all. We figured this was a wiring issue, so just connected the old GPS.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;When trying to use X-CTU to set the power level of the ground XTend radio, we couldn’t connect. We eventually solved this by turning off the plane’s XTend - it was transmitting to the ground XTend and blocking our attempts.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;When attempting our first take-off, the snow presented enough resistance to keep the plane on the ground.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;When attempting our second take-off (with new batteries), the propeller pulled itself off of the shaft.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;When attempting our third take-off, the plane… took off. Wait, that’s not a problem, that’s a good thing. Let’s put it in a new section: Flight&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a video of the flight. It was very bright out and the camera isn’t that great, so it’s very poor quality, but anyway:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were able to fly for a few minutes and collect the key data needed to configure the autopilot. Specifically, we’ll use the typical cruise speed, the amount of throttled used at this speed, and other similar data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the successful flight (and landing), there was one issue while airborne - the RC link to the aircraft was lost for a few seconds at two different points. This is actually a very serious problem since the cause is unknown and if RC is lost for more than a few seconds, the plane will most certainly crash. Here are two plots from after the flight showing the points where the RC link was lost:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Altitude and RC Status vs time&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-EtaE8OgF-
vw/UXIyyG7EHII/AAAAAAAAAEY/eYBPzosEDLE/s1600/RC+Lost+Plot.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-EtaE8OgF-
vw/UXIyyG7EHII/AAAAAAAAAEY/eYBPzosEDLE/s1600/RC+Lost+Plot.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Green: Altitude [m] Cyan: RC Status [good (low), poor (middle), lost (high)]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here we can see that there were significant altitude drops right after each time the RC link was lost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RC Frame rate and RC Status vs time&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-Dovh1nr6joI/UXI1z
GXcf3I/AAAAAAAAAEg/RZ5ff_bodno/s1600/RC+Framerate+Losses.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-Dovh1nr6joI/UXI1zGXcf3I/AAAAAAAAAEg/RZ5ff_bodn
o/s1600/RC+Framerate+Losses.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Green: RC Status [good (low), poor (middle), lost (high)] RC Frame Rate [Hz]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here we can see that the RC link was indeed weakening - as opposed to it being a hardware failure or software bug in the PPM encoder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we’re going to have to do some more testing in an attempt to fix this problem. Over the next days and weeks, we’ll be working hard on this and many more issues that are sure to pop up. Despite being busy, we’ll try to keep making posts, especially once we get to competition, so stay tuned!!!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Volunteering, competition planning, and slow but sure progress</title>
      <link>http://uaarg.com/2013/03/22/volunteering-competition-planning-and/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://uaarg.com/2013/03/22/volunteering-competition-planning-and</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Everyone’s back from reading week and into the home stretch of the semester, and we’re gearing up to get to competition readiness! Recently, however, we’ve also been showcasing our work to students, alumni, and the public at various events.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We volunteered to host a booth at the fifth annual CO2 Powered Drag Car Races hosted by the Faculty of Engineering. UAARG members covered two tables with posters, our airplane, the ground station and a flight simulator. The flight simulator turned out to be very popular! Even the other clubs wanted to play on the flight simulator! The event took place at West Edmonton mall on Friday, March 15th. At the CO2 races, junior high students raced wooden cars powered by CO2 canisters. Between races, students, parents and teachers visited booths hosted by engineering clubs. The UAARG booth was buzzing with people interested in our avionics box, computer simulator and the competition airplane!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-MYrqDbWym5E/UU0v5lWqWWI/AAAAA
AAAAEI/ds3axz9ycK8/s1600/DSC_0472.JPG&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-MYrqDbWym5E/UU0v5lWqWWI/AAAAAAAAAEI/ds3axz9ycK
8/s400/DSC_0472.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UAARG’s Booth at the CO2 Drag Races&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were also present for both the Electrical and Computer Engineering and the Mechanical Engineering First-year Nights, where first-year engineering students have the chance to talk to faculty, alumni, and student groups of their engineering field of interest before choosing what program to specialize in for the remainder of their engineering career. Plenty of interested students approached us; they were interested in everything from our plane’s construction to how we each personally got involved with the club to the ever- popular flight simulator. We also brought our plane and poster to the Faculty of Engineering’s Dean’s Reception for alumni. Many alumni took a keen interest in our project; we were asked some challenging questions about our plane’s systems from some very experienced engineers, one of which had worked with UAARG in the past!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the mechanical front this week, we completed our analysis of the center of gravity (CG) of our airframe and its components. As the picture below shows, we have taken the moment of each component measured from the CG of that component to the motor mount wall as a reference point. From this data, we were able to determine the CG of the aircraft which we need to have 32cm to 34cm back from our reference point. If the CG was too far back the airframe would tail heavy and be very likely to stall and enter an unrecoverable dive. If the CG was too far forward the airframe would fly nose heavy, requiring more power to stay in the air and making landing nose down a more prominent issue. The other benefit is that this allows us to track where our weight is distributed and what will have the greatest influence on the CG.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
Moment=mass*gravity*distance
CG distance=sum of the moments/total mass*gravity
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-iNd_642a0a0/UU0v57mBcsI/AAA
AAAAAAEE/lEUJqi4cYgQ/s1600/Capture+cg.PNG&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-iNd_642a0a0/UU0v57mBcsI/AAAAAAAAAEE/lEUJqi4cYg
Q/s400/Capture+cg.PNG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pie chart of moments of the plane’s components about its centre of gravity&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other news, we’ve been planning for our upcoming competitions in May and June – the Unmanned Systems Canada UAV competition and the AUVSI Student Unmanned Systems Competition. We have selected the attendees of the competitions and are in the process of figuring out the logistics of travel, boarding, etc.; stay tuned for updates as we approach closer to the competition dates!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>It's Reading Week!!!</title>
      <link>http://uaarg.com/2013/02/18/its-reading-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://uaarg.com/2013/02/18/its-reading-week</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s finally reading week!!! A beautiful calm in the center of the storm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve been taking this opportunity to make significant progress. We had a work session on Friday and another on Sunday. We’re having a Critical Design Review on Tuesday in addition to our weekly meeting. We’re also volunteering at WISEST on both Tuesday and Wednesday. Sometime near the end of the week we’ll go flying to do some of our first autopilot testing and likely have a pizza and movie night afterwards to celebrate the progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, for what’s happened since the last post:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Air-frame:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve finalized our design for stronger landing gear and have started construction. The only part we have to build is a simple wooden structure which connects the carbon fiber or metal gear to the plane. Hopefully it’ll be done before testing later this week, but if not, then we’ll use the stock landing gear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Autopilot:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lots has happened with the autopilot. We got our new PPM encoders in last week and got them up and running with the autopilot right away. We’re still not sure what happened to our old one, but the new ones are working great. For those of you not familiar with it, the PPM encoder takes up to 8 PWM signals from the RC receiver and converts them to a single PPM single which the autopilot can understand. This is necessary to use a modern 2.4 GHz RC transmitter with the Paparazzi system which was designed for older, analog transmitters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-moLoDd3CH44/USKT2
hkUvrI/AAAAAAAAADg/RahBCTpR-O8/s1600/IMG_20130205_164150.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-moLoDd3CH44/USKT2hkUvrI/AAAAAAAAADg/RahBCTpR-O
8/s1600/IMG_20130205_164150.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The New PPM Encoders&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also configured Paparazzi to use a switch on the RC controller as a kill switch so that we can bring the plane down even if all we have is the RC link. Previously, we could kill the plane from the ground control station, but if the telemetry link is lost then our only two options are to let the plane try and fly itself home or to take over manual control. If the plane is at the edge of visual range and there are issues with autonomous flight, then neither of these two options are particularly appealing. For those interested in how we did this, take a look at our git repository at &lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/uaarg/paparazzi&quot;&gt;github.com/uaarg/paparazzi&lt;/a&gt; . Or for the particular commit, click &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/uaarg/paparazzi/commit/2d9048ba2836bc3edd36863ccfe82
a94ae1704ef&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s not all we did with the autopilot. We also got our new XTend radios in. These are the radios used to provide the telemetry link between the autopilot and the Ground Control Station. They operate at up to 1 W on the 900 MHz band. Configuring the new radios was simple because we saved our configuration from before. We immediately then went out to test them again. The last time we tested them, we couldn’t get them to work at more than around 100 m. However, we were testing them using a loop-back on the autopilot side. Because of our particular configuration which is optimized for high throughput from the plane to the ground and low, but important, throughput from the ground to the plane, we figured this testing procedure might be part of the problem. So this time, we tested the radios using the autopilot and it’s Ground Control Station. We went out to Quad to see if the radios would work at distances of over 100 m. The image below shows the path the plane was walked through quad:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-iswfqLX9c5k/USKvk_LNVa
I/AAAAAAAAADw/v6fKTkDbFzs/s1600/Telemetry+Test.PNG&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-iswfqLX9c5k/USKvk_LNVaI/AAAAAAAAADw/v6fKTkDbFz
s/s1600/Telemetry+Test.PNG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Walking through Quad with the airplane&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We lost signal after there was no more room to walk without buildings getting in the way. We measured the distance to be 300 m (the yellow line). So it looks like the link is working good. We’ll have to do further testing out in the country to see if it can go 500 m or 1 Km or 4 Km.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last thing we did with the autopilot was figure out a way to configure the on-board radio with it still in the plane, connected to the autopilot. Previously we’ve had to take it out and connect it directly to the computer which has a hassle. Achieving this was surprisingly easy since Paparazzi has code to allow the autopilot board to behave like a USB to serial converter. All we had to do was flash the TWOG with this in the air-frame file:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
&amp;lt;firmware name=&amp;quot;setup&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;target name=&amp;quot;tunnel&amp;quot; board=&amp;quot;twog_1.0&amp;quot; /&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;target name=&amp;quot;usb_tunnel_1&amp;quot; board=&amp;quot;twog_1.0&amp;quot; /&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/firmware&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, the computer that’s connected to the TWOG’s USB port can talk to the radio through the TWOG and we can configure the radio without removing it from the plane.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On-board Software&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Sunday, we took a look at the on-board software to try and fix the segmentation faults we’ve been having. With the Panda Board’s UART RX connected to the autopilot’s TX we could how see the telemetry data going from the plane to the ground. However, the segmentation faults continued. We then configured the FTP server properly and tested that the Panda Board could connect to it. Running the on-board code after this worked. So success!!!! We still have work to do to get a fully functional system though. And we want to re-factor the code to allow it to run even when all the parts aren’t connected (camera, autopilot, FTP server, etc…).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>12/5/13 Meeting Update</title>
      <link>http://uaarg.com/2013/02/05/meeting-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://uaarg.com/2013/02/05/meeting-update</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The past 2 weeks have been relatively quiet, but solid progress towards our goals of flight testing and systems testing in the field are being made.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Testing, debugging, and commenting code were done on both the ground station and onboard imaging over the last few weeks with the aim of fixing some persistent bugs and revising code for clarity. This week’s technical demo was of the onboard camera:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-pb2PZzbh8H4/URGlQ
NDcUYI/AAAAAAAAACo/O0XXURgA2Ak/s1600/2013-02-05+17.30.13.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-pb2PZzbh8H4/URGlQNDcUYI/AAAAAAAAACo/O0XXURgA2A
k/s1600/2013-02-05+17.30.13.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sheldon’s technical demo of the FPV camera with image on a small LCD screen&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sheldon is planning to get the camera mounted to the plane as well as connect it to the plane’s power supply in the next few weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the airframe front, the foam airplanes for flight testing are complete and ready to fly. The team is continuing to try and find a suitable flying field and time for the foamies. In the meantime, potential pilots are training on the flight simulator:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-5rsyUnUiCZA/URGsU
GohHeI/AAAAAAAAAC4/rFoneP2GD80/s1600/2013-02-05+18.00.57.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-5rsyUnUiCZA/URGsUGohHeI/AAAAAAAAAC4/rFoneP2GD8
0/s1600/2013-02-05+18.00.57.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More flight simulator training with the R/C controller&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-iGmEDA0h42I/URGsU
B0d3eI/AAAAAAAAAC8/nlzy44DvunI/s1600/2013-02-05+18.01.22.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-iGmEDA0h42I/URGsUB0d3eI/AAAAAAAAAC8/nlzy44Dvun
I/s1600/2013-02-05+18.01.22.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the completed foamies&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also started work on prototyping a new design for the plane’s landing gear mount.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-J7fvdcnIrAw/URGu7jp-
F1I/AAAAAAAAADQ/ypuTMdwlvWA/s1600/2013-02-05+18.14.29.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-J7fvdcnIrAw/URGu7jp-
F1I/AAAAAAAAADQ/ypuTMdwlvWA/s1600/2013-02-05+18.14.29.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Justin puts his carpentry skills to use&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This design is part of several changes we made to the landing gear to increase overall robustness in the light of several accidents with the landing gear that occurred during competition last year.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>First post, first meeting, and a preview of what's ahead</title>
      <link>http://uaarg.com/2013/01/22/first-post-first-meeting-and-preview-of/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author></author>
      <guid>http://uaarg.com/2013/01/22/first-post-first-meeting-and-preview-of</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the new 2013 UAARG blog! Last Tuesday, we had our first meeting of the new year, in which we discussed work that went on over the holiday break and looked ahead at the final months of work before competition in May.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We reached one of our major goals over the holiday season: completing the Competition Paper for the Unmanned Systems Canada Unmanned Air Vehicle Student Competition, the first of our two major competitions this year. This paper is meant to be a document that outlines the design process of the aircraft and describes its major components and systems, from physical construction and flight to communications and imaging. The paper is also judged toward our final score in the competition, so finishing it was a very large milestone, as well as a large relief, for the team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second major goal reached over the holidays was the completion of the range testing for the communications systems of the aircraft. Several different wireless links are required for both controlled and autonomous flight, as well as transmission of images from the aircraft. The entire system was taken outdoors under conditions similar to those at competition, and the range and capacity of each of the wireless links were tested. Though there are still some problems with communications, the majority of the systems are performing as expected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-R_n04UyK-
yE/UP9PHrevPuI/AAAAAAAAAAs/3ldhmrdXhMU/s1600/IMG_20130105_134943.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-R_n04UyK-
yE/UP9PHrevPuI/AAAAAAAAAAs/3ldhmrdXhMU/s1600/IMG_20130105_134943.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-6nrCRC74u78/UP9PD-
gg2tI/AAAAAAAAAAk/3I1IyclqHJ4/s1600/IMG_20130105_144937.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-6nrCRC74u78/UP9PD-
gg2tI/AAAAAAAAAAk/3I1IyclqHJ4/s1600/IMG_20130105_144937.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/--2gxIfcTL3w/UP9PJ
KsOUbI/AAAAAAAAAA4/IiRDqMaqdEY/s1600/IMG_20130105_144914.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/--2gxIfcTL3w/UP9PJKsOUbI/AAAAAAAAAA4/IiRDqMaqdE
Y/s1600/IMG_20130105_144914.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some photos from the outdoor range testing, including a graph of successful signal transmission&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is still, however, quite a list of items to be completed in the weeks ahead, one of which is flight testing of foam model airplanes so that R/C pilots can be trained for competition. This is a priority at present because of the lack of flight training that the pilots have received so far (flight simulators are fun but no substitute), and we’re going to find an indoor flying field appropriate for this purpose next. We are also working towards having a functional, testable version of the ground station imaging system in a few weeks’ time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-V20pxL7F9Ww/UP9R5
qBK3HI/AAAAAAAAABM/-Sj_iuDICPc/s1600/2013-01-22+18.32.34.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-V20pxL7F9Ww/UP9R5qBK3HI/AAAAAAAAABM/-Sj_iuDICP
c/s1600/2013-01-22+18.32.34.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-zg9ZkMExNO4/UP9R6
PXgy_I/AAAAAAAAABU/5azrZlKNn8g/s1600/IMG_20130122_185623.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-zg9ZkMExNO4/UP9R6PXgy_I/AAAAAAAAABU/5azrZlKNn8
g/s1600/IMG_20130122_185623.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few shots of the foam airplanes under construction for pilot training&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To stay on track in the meantime, we have set several internal deadlines for the completion and testing of major systems before competition. We are also piloting the idea of short presentations by one of the subgroups (airframe, autopilot, imaging, etc.) at the beginning of each meeting; these are meant to familiarize members with all aspects of the plane and its systems, as well as update on progress in subgroups. Stay tuned for updates on the blog as we gear up for the competition season!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    

  </channel> 
</rss>